My name is Louis Raymond Taylor. I'm a
diagnosed psychopath. I was sentenced to
prison for one punch that left a man in
a coma. This is everything I'm
authorized to tell you.
I understand emotions, but I don't feel
them. So, when people say, "How do you
feel about that?" I say, "Well,
actually, I don't. I think about that."
I could go a month and not feel
anything, you know? It's And there's
just every now and again I'll just get a
little flicker and I'll go, "Oh, there's
There I had little something there." I'm
a life coach today. I would not be the
success I am without being a psychopath.
So, I can always remember being a like a
bad, quote, kid and naughty,
mischievous, cheeky. I also remember
also having a a very toxic relationship
with my dad specifically. But, in 2014,
um I'd got back from a extremely chaotic
summer abroad where I was drinking,
fighting every day. I was getting
involved with all sorts of situations. I
would start fights. I would start
trouble. I wanted to feel something. And
you get your adrenaline from doing bad.
When I was fighting, I was fighting to
to hurt, to win, to feel powerful. I
wouldn't stop. Like, um people would
have to drag me off. I would be punching
and punching and stamping and stamping
and stamping. And I got I'm
I am And other people are very lucky
that that didn't
I didn't end up killing somebody. And I
got a bit of a thrill from knowing that
people saw me in that way. And I would
do it for the the attention. I was just
doing anything I could to push things
right to the edge. To the point where I
could die and I didn't care. It seems
like a silly thing, but I would
literally swing from balconies. And I
would be underneath and I'd be swinging
from one arm and just hanging off. And
I'd see everyone going, "Oh my god, you
know, look up there at Louis." And I
would just That for me was more
important. For getting the look at
Louis, he's so crazy, was more important
than I could drop and die. And I
wouldn't even think I could drop and
die. It wouldn't even go through my
mind. Cuz that fear response is just
like numb. And I realized that I I
become an alcoholic because I had no
longer was doing it out of choice and I
realized I now needed to and I was also
still being aggressive. I'd already
committed loads of crimes since the age
of about 13, all sorts of different
ones. The last time I went to prison was
a time that I hit a guy in a taxi queue
and he had a brain hemorrhage and was in
a
coma and then did make a full recovery
but I was sent to prison for 18 months
for grievous bodily harm. I was out one
night
and actually I was I jumped to the front
of the taxi queue.
I don't know if I did it on purpose or I
didn't realize there was a queue or what
have you but some guy shouted, you know,
shouted at me, said something. When I
think about this guy that I hit, all I
can see actually on this occasion is my
dad's face. I was definitely angry cuz
of my dad, he would hit me, he'd be
abusive at me, call me a buffoon. But
this particular time, cuz he was older,
I was 24 by the time this happened and
he was 40. Like I saw that as a as a as
a as an older an old man and um
he shouted at me and I just remembered
just seeing my dad and just punching him
in the face.
And he hit his head head
like flat on the ground. His face flat
on the ground actually
to the point where he was just stone
cold knocked out.
Um and then blood started coming out of
his head. So I thought that's it. I just
looked straight to my left and I saw the
CCTV cameras. I was outside of a train
station at the time and I just thought
that that's that's it, you know. And I'd
like to say I'd like to tell you that my
first thought was the man but it wasn't.
It was it was me. It was I'm going to go
to prison. Um so I put my coat over him
thinking literally thinking he was dead
and then put my hands up and waited for
the police to arrive. And within short
period of time they had to put me in the
back of the car,
sent me to police station.
Luckily he hadn't died
and
I was sent to prison.
Cuz I pleaded guilty at the scene, I got
a lot of time reduced. In the UK you
serve nine months in prison and then you
serve nine months on probation. So I
actually only served nine months inside
prison on that occasion. In probation
like later on I did reach out to him as
a as an opportunity for restorative
justice.
At the time, I honestly couldn't tell
you whether I was doing that just to
you know, tick a box or whatever.
But then later on down the line, I did I
did want to like see if I could contact
him just to see what could happen and
you know, but he he wasn't interested in
in responding. When it happened at the
time, I I don't I don't have those
responses where I think about fear or
what people think or what's going to
happen. There is of course a
inconvenience and a
a frustration of the consequences of the
inevitable prison time that I didn't
obviously didn't want. But there wasn't
there is not associated with fear. It's
not like what's going to happen when I
go to prison. It's just I'm going to be
in prison for a long time.
>> And now looking back, what do you think
about this reaction? What does it make
you feel now with everything that you
know about this?
>> So looking back on it and this is the
most difficult thing for me to share
because this is the thing that paints me
in the in the worst light in terms of
the stereotypical way of people will
perceive it. But they have to truly
understand it. But when I look back on
it now, I feel the same.
Cuz I don't feel anything. I understand
it shouldn't have happened and
you know, what a stupid kid I was and
what an unfortunate situation that man
found himself in and it shouldn't have
happened to him.
Um
but it's just not associated to a
visceral feeling. It's it's associated
to a cognitive understanding of knowing
that you know, that shouldn't have
happened and that's bad and wrong.
Um but whatever remorse or guilt feels
like, I just have no idea what what it
could feel like.
If I could explain psychopathy in one
sentence, I would personally just
describe it as somebody who experiences
the world and emotions differently to
other people. Like so psychopathy
is not in like the DSM manual. You can't
be any more diagnosed with actually just
being a psychopath. You have to have the
underlying clinical condition which is
an antisocial personality disorder which
which what I have. The main traits of
psychopathy are impulsiveness,
um manipulation,
uh there's a very low risk fear
tolerance, as well. It's the emotional
uh bluntness,
um or a complete lack of emotion. And
And that obviously translate to many
things. Lack of remorse, lack of guilt,
uh a lack of concern or care for other
people, if not trained and understood. I
feel almost nothing. And sometimes I'll
use language to just make sense to
people, and I might say the word feel,
but I don't actually feel it. I
understand it. I can get to emotion.
But, I can also just
take it off. Like, I could I can tell I
could never think of something ever
again if I wanted to. Like,
I I if I go, "That's too difficult." I
can just don't think about it. Certain
things like funerals, weddings,
hierarchy of authority, they just don't
really make sense or mean anything to
me. It's only now that I have a social
awareness around the diagnosis that I
really start to compare and contrast
myself against other people and just
realized the disparity of of what I feel
versus what they feel. And then I
realized over time,
especially from dealing with people
one-to-one, that it was actually
everyone
>> [laughter]
>> that was like that. Or most people,
anyway. And I It was me that was
different, you know? It was me that was
probably acting in a way that I
shouldn't have. Now, I can actually ask
the question. I can say to people, you
know, "When this happens, what do you
feel? What sensations are going on in
your body? Do you actually have like a
sinking feeling, a
warm fuzzy? Does it actually feel warm
and fuzzy?" And I can actually
understand that.
I am not emotionless. I just experience
it differently. That's the thing. I know
it's alien to people, but I think it. I
don't feel it, but it doesn't mean to
say it's not there. For example, I have
I have partners. I have love in my life,
but it's just not a felt sense love.
Like, I have to be shown it. I have to
understand it. I have to believe it, you
know? And it becomes as a part of a bond
over time rather than like an immediate
emotional connection. But I know that I
love people. I get to the point where I
can say someone would say, "Do you love
them?" and I can say yes or no. And I
don't know why, but it's just a part of
my brain that's decided that now met
that criteria because of things that
have happened. And I know from my
actions of what I would do for that
person. So, if I would I just going to
sound extreme, but if I would like kill
for that person, then I know that must
mean I love them. So, it's it's kind of
just different, but I make my own map of
the world based on what I have available
and I relate it as close to language and
and a normal human experience of a of a
it's sort of
normal neurotypical person.
>> How about the birth of your first son?
>> Do you know what? So,
when my dad died, I I cried.
Um when a girlfriend cheated on me when
I was younger, I cried.
And I felt it as well. So, so I have had
times where I've been like hurt.
I was really worried I wasn't going to
cry when my son was born
because
I have just would have felt cold. And
when I say feel, it's just I just
there's no way to explain it, but I
would have just reinforced to myself
that I'm this bad, unlovable man that's
going to not be able to break this
pattern with my son that happened with
my dad.
Um I know not everybody does anyway, but
I just wanted to cuz I wanted it to be
the moment where hopefully he could, you
know, bring something out of me that I'm
waiting to see in myself.
Um and he came out and I cried.
So, I was very relieved. I And that was
the first time I've ever cried out of
happiness ever. I've never experienced
that. I've never I didn't know how
people could have emotions for
happiness. It's not It doesn't reach
that intensity for me, right? Very flat.
>> Do you love him?
>> Yes, I love him.
>> So, that's a feeling.
>> [laughter]
>> It's a feeling, but it's like I said,
it's So, if you want me to talk about it
real quickly. So,
I definitely love my son.
This is difficult to admit because I
wouldn't want anyone to I wouldn't want
him to see it and misunderstand it, but
it's different. It's still different.
Like I can't deny it. Like it's stronger
than anything else. I'm able to be away
from him and not think about him every
day. Like I'm able to detach my
emotions. I It took me a while to build
that bond, that connection.
Uh it still feels surreal at times. I'm
probably not as loving as a normal dad
would be, and that's that's a shame to
say cuz
uh you know, I don't wish that upon
myself or anybody because it's a shame
to be this have to say that. Uh but it's
the truth. You know, I want to try and
be as truthful as possible, so
I love him in the ways I've explained,
and he's on the highest end of the
spectrum that hits above that threshold.
Um
but it's probably still less. Um
hopefully by the time he reaches sort of
an an older age, I've worked on myself
even more so that I can show him
that I love him in every aspect that
he's going to feel it and need it and
understand it. Relationships look very
different uh to me because I
I understand like the love languages.
Love languages are different things like
you experience love through physical
touch or through gifts or through acts
of service and present quality time and
different things.
And for me, it has to be um
it has to actually be the acts of
service, which sounds like a really
chauvinistic thing, but it's not.
Because I really like to contribute and
be a good partnership with somebody. I
like to be the provider.
And I like to know that I am, but they
have to show me something back otherwise
I just can't see it. So, I would never
force that upon somebody, but I but if
someone if a woman cooks me a meal, I I
I would feel as close to as you would
perceive loved because I would say
they're doing that because they love me.
It's not you do it because you should.
It's I appreciate that, and I can now
see because if you try and radiate love
to me, I ain't I'm not going to feel it.
That has to be important in a
relationship. It has to be quite a
traditional dynamic like that. I might
not have whatever I just can't whatever
everyone else has. I know that I have an
element of care for people, and I still
want to do the the thing. If anything, I
think it could be more
potent coming from me because I have to
make a logical choice to care. Now I
have what is known as cognitive
emotions. Uh specifically like if we
talk about empathy, which is a big part
of psychopathy,
uh I just don't emotionally relate to
people. Somebody could tell me they
could tell me anything, absolutely
anything, and I wouldn't feel nothing.
And that's not to say I don't care.
Like sometimes I really I am invested in
thinking you've been through a tough
time. You need some help. I'm someone
that help you. I'm going to help you.
And I genuinely want to. Like I'm
invested in doing that because I can see
clearly and understand
even more rationally maybe than some
people with emotions sometimes because
sometimes they're clouded and they're
overwhelmed by emotion to the point
where they're actually have to distance
themselves from that situation. Me,
sometimes I can logically just pull
through that cloud and just help those
people. So it's not that I don't care or
want to help. It's that I just don't
feel it. When I was 17, I had my first
major girlfriend.
And that's something I felt because at
this point I felt very bad and unlovable
because I did I either didn't feel it or
wasn't get getting it or wasn't
receiving it in the way that I could
understand. I just felt unloved. It felt
like a void.
And when I had this girlfriend, she
would invite me around to her family's
house. We'd watch TV.
Um
she would I would talk with her family.
She had lots of brothers and sisters.
And
it was like, "Okay, this is what a
family's like." And I felt something. I
felt like, "Okay, maybe I'm actually
okay because they've accepted me in and
this is this is normal."
But then my alcohol was progressing and
she she had an argument with with me one
night and she just throw threw at me,
"Well, I cheated on you." And it just
really hit me. It to this day I've had
quite a lot of trauma, but I think that
one probably is the one that I remember
feeling the most cuz I felt loss. I felt
confirmation that I was bad and
unlovable.
Um
and I completely
went berserk. Uh and the ambulance
arrived and I was trying to fight them
off and that they pinned me down and
stitched me up and then I escaped from
the hospital and was sectioned under the
Mental Health Act and it was just
complete
Uh and oh yeah, I was screaming telling
them to let me die. That's how like
distraught I was over that. And I think
every
Although I've had some form of emotion
and in these extreme moments it kind of
erupts. And I think with that scenario
it was it felt like loss I think if I
could connect it to what I guess that
would be cuz I in that moment I knew we
would never be together again. I knew it
confirmed to me all the things that I
hoped weren't true about me that I was
this bad and unlovable kid. I was this
wouldn't have happened. And it was
confirmation that I'd lost her
uh and it kind of just hit me all in
that moment.
I was very naughty from young age. I
don't know exactly where that came from
if it was like inherently naughtiness
part of this condition or just who I was
but like um one of my earliest memories
of that kind of my mom coming into
nursery
uh and having to take me
uh home straight away after because it
was a come and see your
see your child at nursery day and uh
everyone else was sitting quiet on the
carpet and I was
running around the room banging a drum
singing happy birthday cuz I was just in
a world of my own. Yeah, I was nearly
expelled from primary school which is
very unusual cuz you get like a
no one really gets expelled from primary
school but I nearly did and I was
expelled from secondary school. I think
my environment played a big factor in
the way that I am. Um I I can't tell you
if we wound back the clock and you know
I had a different upbringing I might be
I might feel all the emotions. I really
couldn't tell you. I really bounce
between thinking to myself no Lewis you
are so different to people that this is
just you you got to accept it and you
got to just allow that to be a part of
who you are to no actually I think I
could be like everyone else and there's
this little tiny flicker of a flame that
keeps on getting snubbed out that maybe
I could
ignite but then but then I go no I
can't.
Some point something must have clicked
for me and I don't remember what
happened where I decided I wanted to be
famous. And this is about 7 or 8 years
old. And I thought okay, I'll do the
normal things you do when you want to be
famous, singing, acting, and dancing.
And I happened to be actually quite
okay. You know, I don't know I don't
know if I was a star but I was actually
I could sing, I could dance, I could
act. Um amateur level. So I did do plays
and stage school and even ballet and tap
dancing which is crazy. So they didn't
get it back at an hour. It's like this
is psychopath kid a psychopath guy
who's violent criminal who was once a
ballerina.
So that's the sort of contradiction of
life. At one of the stage schools I was
at
one of the people at the stage school I
was in
invited me back to his house.
And he was he wasn't like an older man.
He was he was just a lot older than me.
Like on on reflection he was probably 18
and I was probably 10 or 11 but I
actually don't know.
And invited me back to his house. I
thought nothing of it. And then
somehow I managed to
my parents let me sleep over at his
house. And I'm just trying to think
about how that even happened.
I slept over at his house and um
it started normally like watching TV and
then
he like held my hand and it was just the
weirdest thing and I would just froze. I
was thinking why is this guy holding my
hand? But I just but then a minute like
a minute passed I realized I hadn't
pulled my hand away.
And I was thinking oh god and then it
was like
classic bloody
stereotypical climbing on the top bunk.
You know, he came up on the top bunk
where I was at.
And uh
yeah, sexually abused me. And at the
time
I didn't really know what happened cuz I
was so young. I'd never even had any
experiences like that. So I didn't know
like did he did he know this was going
to happen? Did it did I should I have
said like no? Did I participate? Did I
actually do this with him?
No idea.
Um and that was something that I
completely suppressed to the point where
I don't think I even really even
remembered it until I was in rehab 24.
And one of the stories one of the things
I do in in treatment is to get you to
share your life story. And I actually
thought I don't know what that is. So I
had to literally get a bit of paper out
and think okay well
>> [snorts]
>> this happened
and then there and then when I went into
rehab you you go in a group and you
share your story in front of a group.
And I didn't think my story was going to
be that significant at the time cuz I'm
in I'm in here with like heroin addicts
and homeless people and I'm thinking
their stories are going to be crazy and
mine's going to be nothing. And I was
sharing all these things and I just see
their jaw drop to the to ground and I
just thought oh my god this is serious
stuff and that was the first time I'd
ever shared that.
So that was that was significant. I
didn't feel anything at the time apart
from confusion. I don't feel anything
about it now. I don't actually
think it made any difference to me but
it must have done like psychologically
clinically logically you look at it and
you think of course that must have
affected somebody but I couldn't tell
you oh from that day I felt so
whatever cuz I haven't. Um
So anyway that must have had an effect.
I did have an emotionally shut down
family which of course is going to
contribute to the learned behavior. My
dad was very like almost psychopathic.
My mom was very emotionally detached but
I think she showed emotion. I always
thought my family was normal. I knew we
didn't have the best relationship but I
didn't know I couldn't compare it to oh
this should be like this or that should
be like that. They would provide some
parental care in the way that they
understood it but from an emotional
support place it was just non-existent
because they didn't know how to express
that in their own way. So my mom she she
wouldn't really she felt she finds it
very uncomfortable to say I love you or
cuddle
even to this day. She like we we've
tried to make an effort now
but it's still very rare and awkward
when it happens. So
so I know that it's there with her it's
just uh
she wasn't able to share it I think. I
remember from the age of probably 7
years old being so angry and frustrated
with myself because I thought it was my
fault that this relationship um
had broken down between me and my dad.
Every time I even went to speak to him,
it somehow it would turn into a like a
blazing row. He could become uh violent,
but it was it wasn't often. You know, I
I can't say that he beat me all the
time, you know. He did do it um but it
was more the the emotional abuse or um
the things he said. My brother also
actually very emotionally detached.
Uh
we got on to a certain extent because we
were similar in age. He was five years
younger than me.
And I kind of brought him into my
lifestyle really, same sort of group of
friends. I was selling drugs. I got him
to sell drugs for me. That's kind of not
what you would do with your family, but
for me it it did did make it to me it
made it more sense actually. To me it's
like if I'm going to have someone that I
trust, like I would prefer to have my
brother doing this. Most people's
thoughts would be, "What if that
happened? What if this happened? What if
What if that Oh, that's bad. What is he
going to But it just didn't enter my
brain. It started off juvenile sort of
silly and then eventually turned into
things like shoplifting and smashing
windows and
and then drink and drugs.
Started quite small, sort of weed at 13,
alcohol sort of 15, cocaine by the time
I was 18. And at that point I was
addicted to cocaine.
So when I was diagnosed with having an
antisocial personality disorder, it was
a part of the system. So I had just
committed some very violent crimes um
and I was very young. And I've got a lot
of trauma from my life and I think
with the traits of being so impulsive
and reckless and had I had absolutely no
regard for my less myself or my future.
Consequences just was completely out of
my head. So I hurt a lot of people. Uh
not random people, of course. These were
people that had, you know, got into
contact with out on a night of drinking
and what have you. So I went to
probation.
And they do what's called a pre-sentence
report and it's where they kind of
analyze you and your background and your
behavior and your environment to be able
to give a bit of a background package of
information to the judge. I went in
there, crossed my arms, said, "Do what
you want. Don't care." You look at this,
you said, "You're looking at 8 years in
prison." I was like, "So what? Don't
care." Do you not Do you not care about
the people you've hurt? No.
Uh do you not care about what you've
done? No. And I just never thought about
it. I didn't think, "Oh, I'm not
displaying remorse. I'm not" I just
just factually answering the questions
and I did actually did not care
whatsoever.
And she was obviously quite perplexed by
those responses and sent me for a
psychiatric assessment.
I didn't realize that was not normal. I
thought that was just another part of
this court process. Turns out it wasn't.
As it turns out, she noticed something
in me that was unusual.
And then I met
with a psychiatrist. They did an
interview.
Asked me those questions. Nothing really
stood out to me. I didn't think,
"Oh, this is un- this is unusual." I
just thought this is what every criminal
kind of is going to be saying.
And uh yeah, came back with antisocial
personality disorder and I just again, I
just brushed it off and I thought, "Oh,
he's just thinking I'm I'm
mental because I've committed all these
crimes and he's a goody-two-shoes and he
just doesn't know that I'm just being a
bit of a bad lad." I didn't realize
there's anything, you know, wrong with
me, quote unquote.
>> [snorts]
>> And that was the start of the diagnosis.
At the time, I didn't think the
diagnosis was correct. When I was
diagnosed with the antisocial
personality disorder, I don't
think that I shared it that much, to be
honest. I remember with the second one,
with the bipolar, because I'd purposely
gone to get that evaluation.
Um I shared it with I just one I can
remember. I shared it with someone in
the pub and they just said,
I don't I don't remember the exact words
now, but it was something along the
lines of, "I'm glad you figured out what
it was, mate." Like like he knew.
It wasn't this one moment where I'm
like, "I'm a psychopath." You know, it
was like it's
it's
clues and signals and things throughout
my entire life that looking back on it,
they kind of all fit in and you go, "Oh,
yeah, actually." So it's a it's a
evolving process of coming to terms with
any condition that you might have,
right? Back then I had no need to mask,
to display, to try and act, perform. If
someone said, "How did you attack that
man?" I would just tell you exactly how
[clears throat] I attacked them.
Not realizing that maybe I should
probably explain this in a different way
and look a little bit different in how I
I show that information. And as I got
into life coaching, I was I was coaching
people and I was helping people, I would
hear their reactions. I was just
thinking, "Surely not. Like, you cannot
feel that way or think that way and act
that way and feel" and then it was a
pattern. They're all like it. They're
all They're all like this. They all care
about these things. They all react about
nothing, you know? It's out of To me, it
was frustrating because I just didn't
understand it. Sociopaths they still get
a frustrated, aggressive, angry,
irritated. The The worst feelings you
can have is to have
The most common myths about psychopathy
is that they're bad people.
Um they can do bad things and it's much
easier for them to do bad things. They
can manipulate. They can lie. Um they
can harm.
But that is still a choice and that's
largely because they're uneducated and
unaware of who they are. Um and they
haven't learned to
transmute those traits into positive
attributes that can actually be
advantageous. They're told their whole
life they're bad and they're incurable.
So, I don't kind of blame them. I was
almost going to go down that line
myself. I was told, "Expelled from
school, you're bad. Probation,
pre-sentence report, you're bad. The
lawyers, you're bad. The prison, you're
bad." You know, it's
parents, you're bad. Everyone told me I
was bad and I thought I was bad. And bad
people do bad things, you know? Because
that's their identity. That's the person
they think that they are. A lot of
psychopaths
have done bad things and they Those are
the ones you hear of. And the thing is
that not many people want to admit to
psychopathy because of the stigma that
it has associated to it. So, there'll be
great ones out there that just don't
want to tell you because they don't want
to say, "Oh, hey, I've been faking all
this stuff, but I'm still a good
person."
Um but they do great things in the
world. And if we could compare the good
ones and the bad ones, then we'd
probably have a better understanding of
the sort of spectrum that it exists on.
It is only portrayed online in the most
drastic form. Like I said, it's on a
It's on a spectrum. You got psychopathy,
which is on at one end of the spectrum,
which is I don't care about anybody and
I can kill them and and get enjoyment
out of it. And then at the other end of
the spectrum is someone that will, you
know, cry when they hear a piece of
music and they can't stop thinking about
it for the next 3 days because it's
still choking them up every time. So,
there's people that exist all the way on
that spectrum, but we only,
you know, sensationalize the the more
most interesting part of it. But
actually, this is a neurodivergent
mental health condition. You know, I'm
not a bad person. I care about people.
Um I've got a condition. I live with it.
I try my absolute best.
Um but it absolutely shouldn't be
demonized unless you do bad things with
it. And that's only a very select few
people that do. The The population of
psychopaths is 1% of of the world. And
then how many other people are
sociopaths and narcissists and have
disorders? You'd be You'd be surprised.
They don't even know it, maybe. Or
they're hiding it or suppressing it.
They're some of our most successful
leaders that we don't even know about.
Um It's out there. It's just
misunderstood and they're portrayed in a
very negative light. I got a bit of a
thrill out of the violence when I was
younger because it was it was um power.
I felt powerful.
>> [snorts]
>> Um and I could see how that could have
progressed potentially as I got older
and maybe more aggressive and,
you know, edged it closer and closer
that maybe that could have, you know,
turned into some crazy violence. I don't
know.
But I never have any thoughts of harming
people for the sake of harming people.
It's just stigmatized because it's You
hear of serial killers and you think of
psychopaths. I'm a diagnosed psychopath.
I do not get a thrill
out of hurting or doing anything bad.
I could I could do it
but I wouldn't want to. Like it's
stupid. It doesn't make sense why I'd
want to do it but that's because I've
evolved myself to the point where I
understand that.
There is definitely an element of
masking and and putting on personas. I
think we all do it. Like you step into a
meeting and you take the
the confident woman with you if that's
if that's who you need to be. You know,
you you go on a date, you take the
joyful, flirtatious
person with you. You say this you learn
that behavior. That's a skill. And to
say, "Oh, no, I don't do everything I'm
doing is completely genuine." No,
sometimes I do put on a smile when
there's no smile there. You know,
sometimes I do like have a connect like
create a connection when I first meet
somebody because it makes them feel more
comfortable but I don't
don't care to meet them more.
Potentially, I may be more skilled in
certain areas of doing it or it's
it's more conscious than it is
subconscious where people are doing it.
But yeah, different scenarios, different
search circles, different people,
different groups, different outcomes
that I'm looking for.
I will behave differently.
I don't think I'm hiding this monster
within.
Uh there's definitely times where I'm
you know
I'm putting on a bit of a front or there
is something cuz in business sometimes
there is something you want from other
people. You know, sometimes you are in a
meeting and you couldn't care less about
that person's holiday or you know, how
nice that tie is. Not that I make
comments on things like that but the
point I'm making is sometimes I couldn't
care less and I don't like that person
but I might pretend that I do. Um but
yeah, there's no monster waiting to
pop out around the corner and as soon as
you close the door there's this
different version of me. There is a
different version of me but it's not a
monster. It's a quieter it's
more introverted. It's a more dull it's
a more baseline version of me.
>> I would not be
the success I am without being a
psychopath because it's been my massive
advantage. I have a ability to
strategically think because I have to
overcompensate for the lack of feeling.
So, I can create a plan and I can see
every step that needs to take place.
Sometimes people have like a goal and
they don't they they can't visualize how
to get there and that's just some way
some people are. I seem to be very
methodical and strategic in my way of
kind of taking very simple steps one
after another with no emotional burden
pulling me back. We created the business
called The Coaching Masters.
And
the business grew exponentially. It was
right before the pandemic. It was all
online. We knew that had to be online
from the start. The main thing we do
is we help people become life coaches.
Those 15,000 students, they're people
that have wanted to become a coach and
they're now qualified as life coaches.
That's the main part of our business
now. You see a psychopath as
manipulative and I am very manipulative
but to help someone. I will persuade you
to think better about yourself and live
your life beyond your wildest dreams.
It's just categorized as bad if you're
manipulating somebody to do something
that's harmful for them or beneficial
for you. So, manipulation can become
persuasion. My uh impulsivity can be
seen as being able to take risks. My
lack of fear enables me to not be
burdened by it. Um my emotional
bluntness allows me to make logical
decisions rather being influenced by
emotion and fear and ridicule and
embarrassment or those things that might
happen to people. It's like every single
negative trait has a positive and it's
about trying to integrate them and allow
them and see rather than trying to
dismiss it cuz some people might think,
"Oh, I'm quite manipulative sometimes.
I'm going to bury that." But actually,
why not try and accept that as part of
something that you do, but just make
sure that you're doing it
constructively. So, I'm able to
integrate
those negative aspects of myself, but
use them for good.
>> How do you feel about people who might
think, "Okay, this is not real then?"
>> Mhm, loads of people do. I've been
called a cult leader. And there's an
element of truth behind it, right?
Because when people say, "You're
exploiting people for personal gain."
I think, "Well, yeah, a business is for
personal gain." Of course, like I'm not
just doing this because I want to help
everyone. I want to build a business. I
want to make money. It's no different
than any other leader of an
organization. Now, I'd be lying if I
said I got everyone results because it's
impossible to get everyone results. They
need to want it. I can coach, I can
help, and I can make impact. But if you
want a real transformation, it's
self-led. So, the ones that don't win, I
couldn't care less.
And I'll tell you why.
Not my fault.
I will give you all the resources, all
the skills, all the support, and I go
over and beyond. Like, I will give you
everything. But if you don't make it
work, it's down to you. Do you think
that universities are upset because they
have a 3% success rate of people that
actually get jobs in their their field
of They're educators. They can provide
the skills and resources, but it's down
to the person. I know it works. I've
helped thousands of people. If I was in
a a like a a one-off scenario where it
only works for me, and everyone else it
didn't work for cuz I'm teaching them
how to be psychopaths, of course that
wouldn't be fair. But I'm not. I've
educated myself. I know what it works,
and I've proven it.
It can multiple across thousands of
people from different countries and
different walks of life and different
demographics. So, I know it works. So,
if it doesn't work for you, that's down
to you. And you'll probably find that
the person that doesn't work for,
probably nothing's working for them. A
lot of people have over complicated the
world. They worry about things that are
never going to happen. And I just look
at these people, and I just think, "Your
life is just running out." Like, your
life is literally running out, and all
you're doing is stressing yourself out
and worrying and scared about things
that don't exist. And I think, "Wow,
that must That's not how it's supposed
to be." So, there's obviously that part
that I'm quite grateful that I don't
have to be wrapped up in. There's a lot
of ambitious people that want to achieve
a lot with their life and they know the
things to do but they don't do them cuz
they're held back by that fear, the fear
of their own insecurities and doubts and
what might happen or won't happen and
actually if you can look at it quite
logically, but a lot of people ask me
how I'm successful and I just say,
"Well, I figure out what I want to do
and then I make like a plan of 1 2 3 and
then I take steps 1 2 and 3."
I'm not some crazy genius with these mad
plans. I just actually do all the things
I want to do cuz most people could do
the exact same things but they're just
held back by those emotional
constraints.
There's a lot of successful people that
will detach themselves from their
emotions purposefully, you know, because
it's helpful in situations. You know,
politicians, CEOs, surgeons, these
people may actually be on this, you
know, psychopathy spectrum but even if
they weren't, they would have to make a
conscious choice to distance themselves
cuz if they were in the middle of
surgery, "Oh my god, but what about if I
clip that? Or what about what the pa-
what their parents or their family or
their daughter going to I can't operate.
I'm going to have to let them just bleed
out because, you know, what about if
something goes wrong?"
Dead. You know,
they're dead. Or what about if they go
to war? It's like, "Can I kill 100,000
people with that decision or
800,000 people with that decision? I
can't kill those 100,000 people so
now they're all dead." You know, you
have to go 100,000 people just makes
more sense. Do you know what I mean?
So, some people have the ability to
either
disconnect or it's just disconnected
anyway but of course can be helpful.
From a corporate sort of point of view,
I wouldn't say I'm the best leader in in
in in in business. I I I definitely see
it having flaws. I find it very
difficult to
communicate
to people.
I I I I assume they think how I think a
lot of the time.
And, um, I get very frustrated when they
don't understand or don't do things the
right way because I I don't know how
they wouldn't be able to do it cuz to
it me it feels very,
um, simple.
And not in arrogant way but I just I see
it clearly sometimes and they don't and
I find it frustrating to communicate
that sometimes to to staff.
And um I don't have much of a tolerance
to support them emotionally from that
real strong leadership perspective. I
know that's the right thing to do.
Nurture staff, employees, build them up.
I really don't have the tolerance or the
time or the patience uh in in that. So,
I become more of a
um [snorts]
sort of more of a dictator sort of ship
uh kind of leadership style. And it
works to a certain extent, but um I
don't think it's the best doing it, to
be honest. I think when you you're
changing things so fast and you're
working so quickly and you just want to
build something and you've got a vision
for it, sometimes you don't have the
space to nurture people and give them
creative freedom to do their own thing
because I've got my vision and I don't
know what I want to do. So, I end up
just barking orders and telling them
what people want to do and sometimes it
works, sometimes it doesn't, but if we
move fast enough, we still end up
building quite well. I'm very happy that
my life has has made this massive
change. Um happy's an interesting one
for me because I don't feel a strong
happiness. I I have a flatness, but I do
have a a sense of being
Content's also quite difficult, I would
say. I'm on a climb. I know I'm on a
climb. I I have this
illusion that the higher I climb, the
the more complete and fulfilled I'm
going to feel. I know because I'm
educated enough to know that that's not
going to happen, but I allow myself to
carry that climb because it gives me the
satisfaction of knowing that I'm working
towards something. I know eventually I
might hit a peak. Call me a psychopath,
call me a manipulator, call me a
grandiose. I call that confidence. Call
me, you know, whatever you might you
know, whatever attribute you think. I'm
okay with myself and who I am and I'm
okay with the impact I'm having and I
know I'm not making any negative uh
impact on anybody else.
The bizarre thing is when I was uh told
that you'll end up in prison, a part of
me actually
liked the idea of it because I always
knew that I was going to do something
significant with my life. When I went to
prison the first time as a young
offender in the young offenders
institution, it was chaotic, but I like
I I like kind of like the excitement of
it, you know? It was
It's fun in a way. It was like a
different adventure because it's new,
it's a different environment, meeting
new people. It's just like being in an
action movie in a way. So, it's part of
it is fun. And everyone was asking me
kind of what you in for, what you in
for, and I always had to respond with
these very like menial crimes at the
time. And I remember thinking like I
wish that I could say something a bit
more impressive. And that's like how you
rank. The more longer your crime and the
more bad it is that the higher you rank,
really. So, I I remember thinking
I could actually do with a better charge
next time.
So, if anything, I was kind of waiting
to go back. There was a big gap between
the first and the second time I went
prison, 18 and 19. It wasn't until I was
24 in the end that I was I got went
back. I wasn't in the young offenders
anymore. I was in the the adult prison.
And a bit more mature. It still had the
same effect because I could say what you
in for still happens. And like I was
able to say grievous bodily harm. It's
just enough to say, "Okay, he's just a
standard offense and also, you know, he
can he can fight."
So, that was I always remember thinking
this is a perfect. I didn't have any
like
opportunity to connect with people in
prison cuz it's just very transactional.
People are coming from different wings,
different prisons, in and out, getting
released, coming in. So, you know, you
you you form people that you get
acquainted with and you you know, you
talk to, but it's just, you know, so
surface level, you know, so I decided to
do maths and English whilst I was in
there. And the only reason I did that
was because they pay you.
You can only spend £15.50 a week maximum
even if you're a multimillionaire cuz
everyone's got to be the same on your
toiletries, your stamps, your
um your food, your snacks, everything.
Um but I didn't even have that. So, I
needed to get paid and they pay you £10
to work like cleaning the wing or £11
for education. So, you get an extra
pound.
So, that's why I went to education, to
be honest, for the extra pound a week. I
was 24 at this point, but I was acting
like a child. Like I would screw the
paper up, throw it around, you know, I'm
not doing this. And the prison tutor,
Susie,
lovely lady,
and she just came and sat down next to
me, and she just said, "What's the
matter?" And I actually don't think
anyone had asked me that before.
And I said, "I don't understand."
And that was really confusing because
I'd like vocalizing these sort of
subconscious thoughts I'd never even
really explored, just from simple
questioning. That I
And I And I thought, "How do I How do I
not even know I understand cuz I've not
even looked up at the board. You know, I
don't even know what you're teaching me.
But how do I say I understand?"
And then kind of for a few different,
you know, thoughts and questions and
chats, I realized it was kind of more of
a
not wanting my dad to be right because
he would call me a buffoon and stupid.
Uh so I thought I was. I I I was
convinced I was stupid and, you know,
incapable of learning. So I wouldn't
even try. It was just this weird
confusion thing that I wasn't even aware
of. That's how
crazy it is. It just happens. And
through understanding it a little bit, I
thought I can give it a try and I
started to learn maths and English and
pick it up quickly. Of course, it was
simple, and that was a big turning point
where I was like, maybe I could And I
would sit to the prison tutor, Susie, I
said, "Do you think I could go to
university?" And I was I was almost like
expecting her to go, "Don't be so
stupid. Of course, you can't." You know,
cuz that's that's what I thought. I left
school, was expelled at 15, but we could
leave at 16 back then. And she just
looked at me, and she just said,
"Of course, you can."
And
it I I believed her, actually. I I
thought, "Actually, you You actually
believe I can." So that that gave me a
goal. I said, "Right, I'm going to get
out of there. I'm going to go to rehab
and
I'm going to go to university."
>> Do you think that had she come 10 years
earlier, it would have had the same
impact on you?
>> I mean, I would have liked to have Susie
in my life sooner. I think that would
have been
definitely advantageous, but who knows,
you know, they say you you can take a
horse to water, but you can't make it
drink. Maybe that was the perfect time
in my life where she needed to intervene
and and give me that clarity. And maybe
I would have Cuz to be To be I was
dismissive of help. Like it would have
probably been presented itself to me
because I remember like when I had this
breakthrough moment inside prison uh
where I realized that I wanted to change
and that I could change,
everything started becoming different. I
see signs on the wall for therapy and AA
meetings and stuff that I didn't see
before. It's like my brain was actually
like in NLP, we talk about it, deleting,
distorting, generalizing information
through our filters. And it's a real
thing. Like, I was It's not my
perspective of the world. My world was
physically different from changing my my
um changing myself, changing my
thoughts.
And so, the moment I decided I wanted to
work on myself, I saw these
opportunities and all these people that
wanted to help. And when they did
approach me to help me, I would I would
engage with it and I would realize that
they were very helpful. But before, I
just brushing off, brushing off,
ignoring it, ignoring it. So,
you know, who knows? Susie could have
come into my life earlier and it could
have helped. Or maybe it wouldn't have
been the right time.
I did this rehabilitation of addictive
prisoners trust program inside prison.
And that was a game-changer, that was.
It was so basic but enough to give me a
glimpse of what I could learn. When I
was about to be released after 9 months,
I applied for this 6-months fully
intensive rehabilitation treatment
center in Portsmouth, right on the south
coast, hours and hours away from where
I'm from.
And you can go to this full rehab and
then you can like resettle there and get
housing allowance and start a new life.
I got released from prison, they picked
me up, they escorted me right down to to
rehab.
And
that was worse than prison because it
was not the lovely retreat with yoga and
mindfulness that I was sort of thinking
in my head. It was this break you down,
this get all the trauma out, this
rebuild you, this tell you how bad this
is, let's get you out of denial, let's
make this uncomfortable. All I wanted to
focus on is my recovery cuz I knew that
was the first thing I needed to fix. If
I can't fix the drug and alcohol, that's
going to let me clear like think clearly
and give me the space to do everything
else. So, that That my number one
priority. I can't tell you exactly how
that breakthrough moment happens. I
think sometimes they did say they happen
out of nowhere. It's just like a moment
that just clicks. It absolutely did
break me down and build me back up. I've
gone from
a violent criminal drug addict to being
a volunteer in Portsmouth going to AA
meetings on a Friday night and having a
milkshake after for the enjoyment after
the meeting and I'm thinking I need I
can see the progress now. When I looked
in the mirror and and saw myself, it was
just a truthful reflection. It was the
version of me that's not blaming and not
looking for a way out and not being in
denial and just an honest representation
of
we are where we are, Lewis, and you are
the problem. You have to accept that,
but you have to also set accept that
once you realize you're the problem,
you're also the solution. We can make
changes.
So, my dad in the end
he was an alcoholic, by the way, and he
got pancreatic cancer from that.
And I didn't know how to process that at
the time, but he lost all of his weight
and become very old very quickly and he
got a terminal diagnosis and I just
distanced myself from it cuz I didn't
know how to deal with it. So, he went to
the hospital and then the next day we
went to visit him and the nurse hadn't
let me know that he'd died. So, I walked
straight in through the room and I just
saw him dead and
and that was just a very very shocking
moment.
But then I just suppressed everything
and I just went out and took drugs and
took alcohol and just life went on and
suppressed all of that.
Cuz there was emotion from those things,
for sure. Like I didn't experience that
one cuz I definitely blocked that out,
but
>> go to the funeral?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> How was the funeral?
>> I thought
it was a funeral. I really I
the worst I don't know. That's too far.
I was going to say No, I'll be honest. I
the first thought that came to my mind
was boring. But that's
it's cuz they're all the same, aren't
they? I don't cuz again
I don't really get the concept of things
like that. My dad's my biggest trauma. I
I did say like the girlfriend hit me the
hardest, but I think my dad's the
biggest trauma. Like I know that his
words affected me the most, and there's
definitely something unresolved there.
I've done a lot of work on it. I think
there's more to do. I wouldn't say it's
chapter closed. I'd say it's
it's put neatly, nicely in a box at the
point where it's at a good position now.
Uh and it felt good to to work on it,
but I've got more to do. I've done all
sorts of therapy, psychotherapy, the
rehab, the
you know, all sorts of things from a
mindset perspective, and I came became
very strong in my mindset, I believe.
But there was still a lot of healing and
a lot of emotional work that I wanted to
do. So I did try all sorts of different
uh unconventional things like plant
medicines in Bali.
Um
Like all sorts of different things like
somatic work and energy healing. And the
one that really worked was breathwork.
Maybe the last 5 years I've been writing
a book.
And it's called Unlimited. How to turn
adversity into an asset. And that's the
key message. It's how to take anything
that's ever happened to you or any
negative trait or flaw or thing you've
done, and how to use that for positive.
And how to use that as something that
you can actually be grateful for.
Not only to relieve that mental burden,
but also to actually use the assets and
the resources that are available to you
because you don't realize that they are
in disguise some of your best traits.
Like I never would have thought that my
psychopathic traits would help me become
a millionaire. Like but they are there.
And there are clues in success that
aren't often shared because they're
controversial. There are many successful
people who have become success in a
certain way, but then teach it in a
different way because they can't really
share what they've actually done. But
I'm actually completely okay with saying
this is how this is how it is. I'm
maturing. I'm learning new things.
That's recalibrating the way and
perspectives that I have. And or I'm
remembering other things. Or I get
interviewed and asked get asked
different questions that trigger
different things in my mind. For now,
I'm content knowing that I'm developing,
I'm being successful. I have the
significance that I've been craving all
my life in a positive way that is
sustainable. Like if anyone ever told me
that I'd be on TV, doctor, millionaire,
all these crazy things, I would think
you are crazy cuz I just I would have
been happy with a stable job and not
taking drugs. So of course I'm happy
about it. Does it give me that real deep
internal content, fulfillment, happiness
that yeah, I've made it and I'm who I
am? No.
Can I get there? I hope so. Am I there
yet? Not sure. But I'm on an
ever-evolving quest. Like I'm 10 years
into this journey, but I'm 36 years old.
I've got another, you know, hopefully
another 50, 60, 70, 100 years, who
knows, um to keep on evolving.
>> Hi, I'm a producer and authorized
account. If you enjoyed this video, then
please subscribe and comment with more
topics that you'd like us to cover in
this series.